every home gym needs a rock solid weight
bench and this one from Deus has really
caught my eye lately it has a 3X3 in 11
gauge steel build so it has that 1000lb
weight capacity and there's vertical
storage I've been using this bench for a
while now and I'm really excited to tell
you guys all about it so let's get right
to
[Music]
it
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to be talking about the
Deus adjustable weight bench if you're
new to this whole process in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
there is to know about this bench but
specifically we're going to talk about
some pros and cons some money and then
of course who should or maybe should not
add this to their home gym but before I
do all that just want to make sure you
guys know that we've reviewed a lot of
other weight benches on barb. comom and
we went ahead and came up with our own
best list so if you want to check that
out all you got to do is search barbin B
best weight benches it's going to pull
right up for you and you can find out
for yourself which ones we like the
[Music]
best so I really like how this bench
features 3x3 in 11 gauge steel tubing
for the framework now the actual weight
capacity is not listed on the Deus
website but you know I've tested a lot
of other weight benches and typically a
bench of this stature has 1,000lb weight
capacity now of course that's still
including your body weight but 1,000 lb
is 1,000 lb and so that should you know
suffice the needs of basically every
single athlete out there especially a
home gym athlete now you have 10
different backpad adjustments ranging
from 0 de to 88° and then three
different seat pad adjustments from 0
degre to 33° so you got a lot of
Versatility right there there are some
cons though with this bench first one
being that it's not an FID bench meaning
flat incline decline so there are not
any decline positions available on this
bench that's what you're looking for I
definitely suggest you go and look
elsewhere it's also you know one thing
here is that the back pad is 10 and 1
half inches wide that's kind of narrow
you know a lot of people like a 14inch
12 in is kind of my sweet spot a lot of
people like a 14inch though because it
creates more stability for your
shoulders so you know if you have a wide
back or maybe you just don't enjoy that
narrow design I definitely go look
elsewhere as well another thing here is
that the seat pad this gets a little
nitpicky but it's actually it's just a
perfect square a lot of people like a
taper design with their seat on their
bench you're not going to get that here
definitely just remember that it's also
kind of expensive it's typically 700
bucks right now it's 500 but you know
that's still a lot considering it's not
an FID bench plus it weighs 110 lbs so
it could be a little difficult for some
people to move it
around so once again the Deus adjustable
weight bench typically costs about 700
bucks but right now it's around 500 I
personally think you know the actual
quality of work here is worthy you know
of that that price tag this bench is
basically a spitting image of the Rogue
adjustable bench 3.0 I mean almost every
single aspect is the exact same that
one's about 600 so you know with this
little sale they're doing right now on
this bench you're getting actually
you're getting a pretty good deal
however if it was me I'm going to buy a
bench I'm looking for one that has
decline adjustments available and one
that comes to mind is the rep Fitness
Black Wing 600 bucks has 11 gauge steel
build closed ladder design just like
this one and it has vertical storage so
the fact that you are getting you know
that extra versatility with the decline
available I think it makes it you know a
little bit better of a purchase I guess
you could say this is still a really
good bench though I just wish that it
had a decline angle
[Music]
available all right so all in all this
bench only took me about 20 minutes to
put together really easy all you got to
do is assemble the padding and then the
back foot really straightforward like I
said really easy to do speaking of the
padding I really like it now remember
this is 10 1 12 in wide right here so
it's kind of narrow compared to a lot of
other benches it's fine by me you know I
don't feel uncomfortable when I'm doing
my bench pressing or anything but I
definitely understand why people want a
wider one because you have more
stability on your shoulders which
definitely goes a long way as far as the
actual padding goes this vinyl is really
comfortable to lay on it's about 2 and 1
half inches thick so a lot of support
and comfort but I also like how it's
textured it's kind of grippy It kind of
grips your back a little bit so if you
sweat you know you're not going to be
sliding around or anything you're not
going have to worry about that at all
so you know like I said earlier it gets
a little you know nitpicky when it comes
to this actual seat pad this resembles a
flat bench you know most flat benches
they're just squared off not the case
with all adjustable benches you know a
lot of them kind of taper in the front
you know it it that's really a personal
preference it's not like it's
uncomfortable I just prefer you know
kind of having that taper up front right
here I really like this front foot
design it's kind of like a tripod
doesn't get in the way of your feet at
all as you go to get set up for your
bench presses I mean look I can get my
feet right up in here and it's you know
nice and comfortable which is definitely
a good thing I love this knurled handle
right here on the front stainless steel
just really easy to grab and the
placement it it like I said it's easy to
grab and it doesn't make this 110 lb
bench really feel like it's 110 lb it's
pretty easy to move it around but still
kind of heavy you have three different
adjustments right here for the seat it's
really easy to do just lift up and it's
going to you know be nice and secure I
really love these stainless steel rails
it just looks awesome it's just very
aesthetically pleasing in the back right
here once again you still have that
stainless steel rail so it's ranging
from 0° to
88° I like that you also have the laser
engraved numbering right there on the
front as well and you know to adjust it
it's really easy you know ladder Styles
all you have to do is pull up to you
know pull it up but whenever you go to
put it back down you got to grab one of
these handles and you can easily glided
into place back here on the back is that
vertical storage really comes in handy
just pick it up and set it down and
because this is a closed ladder don't
have to worry about this you know
swinging out or anything cuz it's going
to get stuck right there so it stays
nice and secure so if you're looking for
a bench that's going to offer a lifetime
of usage I definitely think this fits
the build it's got that 11 gauge steel
build so it's definitely durable and it
has a powder coat finish so it's going
to add to that durability plus it has
vertical stor storage so you if you're
tight on space and you really need that
you know extra space just to you know
tuck your bench away when you're done
that definitely comes in handy not every
single weight bench offers that
especially even at this price point so
that's definitely you know a very good
thing going for it only reason my
opinion two reasons to not purchase this
bench is if you're looking for a bench
that has a decline adjustment available
because remember this is not an FID
bench and then really it's just the
money you know this is a $500 bench I
think it's worthy of the price tag but
not everybody wants to spend $500 on a
weight bench bench there's plenty of
other benches that are under 400 bucks
that are FID benches 11 gauge steel
whatever and they're going to last you
just as long so honestly that's it for
[Music]
me all right well that's a wrap on
today's review over the deuse adjustable
weight bench I've been really impressed
with this I think it's going to offer a
lifetime of usage only thing I wish it
had was decline adjustments thanks for
watching y'all I hope this video was
helpful and I was able to tell you
everything there is to know about this
bench as always stay posted for my next
video but for now head over to Barb
and.com cuz we have a full written
article that I definitely think you
should check out all you got to do is
type in Deus adjustable weight bench
review it's going to pull right up for
you you can go over every single thing
we talked about here today I'll catch
youall next
time
my
heart